[
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "401",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَلَا يَعْلَمُ إِذَا بُعْثِرَ مَا فِي الْقُبُورِ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانَ",
        "answer": "mankind",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insāna",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ لِرَبِّهِ لَكَنُودٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بُعْثِرَ",
        "answer": "will be scattered",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 138,
        "tlit": "buʿ'thira",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَلَا يَعْلَمُ إِذَا بُعْثِرَ مَا فِي الْقُبُورِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب ع ث ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to overturn, to scatter",
        "waznTlit": "bā ʿayn thā rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَثَرْنَ",
        "answer": "Then raise",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 212,
        "tlit": "fa-atharna",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَثَرْنَ بِهِ نَقْعًا",
        "rootWord": "ث و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ث و ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to raise, to plough",
        "waznTlit": "thā wāw rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَمْعًا",
        "answer": "collectively",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "jamʿan",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَوَسَطْنَ بِهِ جَمْعًا",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمْع",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "jamʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِحُبِّ",
        "answer": "in (the) love",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 284,
        "tlit": "liḥubbi",
        "frequency": "95",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهُ لِحُبِّ الْخَيْرِ لَشَدِيدٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "has endeared",
        "waznTlit": "ḥubb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحُصِّلَ",
        "answer": "And is made apparent",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 327,
        "tlit": "waḥuṣṣila",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحُصِّلَ مَا فِي الصُّدُورِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح ص ل",
        "waznEnglish": "to make apparent",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā ṣād lām",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَخَبِيرٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely All-Aware",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 385,
        "tlit": "lakhabīrun",
        "frequency": "52",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّهُمْ بِهِمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ لَخَبِيرٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَبِير",
        "waznEnglish": "your news",
        "waznTlit": "khabīr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخَيْرِ",
        "answer": "(of) wealth",
        "pcklId": "153",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "l-khayri",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهُ لِحُبِّ الْخَيْرِ لَشَدِيدٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِرَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "to his Lord",
        "pcklId": "967",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "lirabbihi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ لِرَبِّهِ لَكَنُودٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّهُمْ",
        "answer": "their Lord",
        "pcklId": "968",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbahum",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّهُمْ بِهِمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ لَخَبِيرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَشَدِيدٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely intense",
        "pcklId": "101",
        "rootWordId": 762,
        "tlit": "lashadīdun",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهُ لِحُبِّ الْخَيْرِ لَشَدِيدٌ",
        "rootWord": "ش د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَدِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "and harden",
        "waznTlit": "shadīd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَشَهِيدٌ",
        "answer": "surely (is) a witness",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 801,
        "tlit": "lashahīdun",
        "frequency": "160",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهُ عَلَىٰ ذَٰلِكَ لَشَهِيدٌ",
        "rootWord": "ش ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَهِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) witnessing",
        "waznTlit": "shahīd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صُبْحًا",
        "answer": "(at) dawn",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "ṣub'ḥan",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُغِيرَاتِ صُبْحًا",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُبْح",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "ṣub'ḥ",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصُّدُورِ",
        "answer": "the breasts",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 827,
        "tlit": "l-ṣudūri",
        "frequency": "46",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحُصِّلَ مَا فِي الصُّدُورِ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدْر",
        "waznEnglish": "will proceed",
        "waznTlit": "ṣadr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَبْحًا",
        "answer": "panting",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 879,
        "tlit": "ḍabḥan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْعَادِيَاتِ ضَبْحًا",
        "rootWord": "ض ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ض ب ح",
        "waznEnglish": "panting",
        "waznTlit": "ḍād bā ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْعَادِيَاتِ",
        "answer": "By the racers",
        "pcklId": "102",
        "rootWordId": 967,
        "tlit": "wal-ʿādiyāti",
        "frequency": "106",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْعَادِيَاتِ ضَبْحًا",
        "rootWord": "ع د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰدِيَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "transgress",
        "waznTlit": "ʿādiyāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "he know",
        "pcklId": "378",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamu",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَلَا يَعْلَمُ إِذَا بُعْثِرَ مَا فِي الْقُبُورِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْمُغِيرَاتِ",
        "answer": "And the chargers",
        "pcklId": "153",
        "rootWordId": 1095,
        "tlit": "fal-mughīrāti",
        "frequency": "154",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُغِيرَاتِ صُبْحًا",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُغِيرَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "so they will surely change",
        "waznTlit": "mughīrāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُبُورِ",
        "answer": "the graves",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1171,
        "tlit": "l-qubūri",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَلَا يَعْلَمُ إِذَا بُعْثِرَ مَا فِي الْقُبُورِ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْر",
        "waznEnglish": "and provides a grave for him",
        "waznTlit": "qabr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدْحًا",
        "answer": "striking",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1179,
        "tlit": "qadḥan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُورِيَاتِ قَدْحًا",
        "rootWord": "ق د ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق د ح",
        "waznEnglish": "striking",
        "waznTlit": "qāf dāl ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَكَنُودٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely ungrateful",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1294,
        "tlit": "lakanūdun",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ لِرَبِّهِ لَكَنُودٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ن د",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) surely ungrateful",
        "waznTlit": "kāf nūn dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَقْعًا",
        "answer": "dust",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1511,
        "tlit": "naqʿan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَثَرْنَ بِهِ نَقْعًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ق ع",
        "waznEnglish": "dust",
        "waznTlit": "nūn qāf ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْمُورِيَاتِ",
        "answer": "And the producers of sparks",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1604,
        "tlit": "fal-mūriyāti",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُورِيَاتِ قَدْحًا",
        "rootWord": "و ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُورِيَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "to hide",
        "waznTlit": "mūriyāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَوَسَطْنَ",
        "answer": "Then penetrate (in the) center",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1608,
        "tlit": "fawasaṭna",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "100",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَوَسَطْنَ بِهِ جَمْعًا",
        "rootWord": "و س ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَسَطْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to penetrate the center",
        "waznTlit": "wasaṭ",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    }
]